Well, for a decade now, we have found
ourselves in one of the southern states
to kick off the USA downhill series.
Hello and welcome to Windrock Bike Park.
We're deep in the Appalachian Mountains
just outside of Knoxville for the 10th
[music] running of the Red Bull
Tennessee National. My name is Rob
Warner. I'm alongside Elliott Jackson
and Elliott, first time here for me,
first time in the south. I'm absolutely
loving it. What a place to be.
>> Oh man, get me back to USA downhill. I
haven't been here I haven't been to a
USA downhill race, a big race since I
was racing and it's just nothing like
the camaraderie here, the scenery, the
the track is just incredible. America, I
mean it's incredible. It's absolutely
brilliant, yeah. And of course, we have
got I would say a phenomenal rider
lineup, right? Well, I think that the
talent in the US has has been making
leaps and bounds. I think the big story
to me is Aaron Gwin. Fourth last year, a
second off of Amaury Pierron, but this
year he's on Frameworks just focusing on
being that athlete that we know he can
be.
>> Bull Hardline Tasmania, I mean he is on
form. So, I want to see what he can do,
but of course it's a who's who. Ronan
Dunne, Ollie Calvert, Dante Silva,
national champion Neko Mulally, Neko
Mulally, Neko Mulally, Neko Mulally,
Neko Mulally, Neko Mulally, Neko
Neko Mulally, Neko
>> Too many Americans to mention. One we've
got to mention though is Dakota Norton,
the most successful here, four wins at
this Red Bull Tennessee National. So,
he'll be one to keep an eye on. What
about the women? Who do we look for
there? Well, I think the two names that
we know and love Frida Rönning and
Kailey Skelton, the national champion,
current national champion. Last year,
Eleonora Farina just blew everyone's
mind. Four seconds, yeah, four seconds
ahead of Marine Cabirou. Massive result
for Yeah, and when you when you do that,
especially as a junior, the next year
there is a lot more pressure and she
just really just wants to back that up.
>> Pressure's on. Pressure's on. Okay.
Well, of course, this is Aaron Gwin's
bike park and as you'd expect, the
racetrack is absolutely full on. Here's
what some of the racers think of it.
Well, Cole, I think it's fair to say
that you know this track inside out. You
built it. Where do you see riders making
time? You must know all the intricacies
of this place. As you know, it's it's
super dry out there. Everyone's sliding
around. Heard a couple broken wheels
yesterday. I myself got a flat.
>> Do you think the track's going to break
down now? Is it going to start getting
looser and dustier or will it stand up?
I mean, it's pretty hard packed. I think
you're still going to have the silt on
top, but there's a lot of those like
little gravelly baby heads coming out.
So, you got to definitely watch out for
those on the inside corners and stuff.
Is this about as fast as this place
runs? Oh, as fast as it runs.
Honestly, it's scary right now, yeah.
You came close last year, less than a
second off the win. What does it take to
win on this track? Cuz riding it myself
yesterday, it's pretty fast, right? It's
pretty open. I would say the overall
flow of the track is definitely fast.
Like it's especially when it's dry like
this, the dirt here is pretty hard when
it's dry. Minus the pedals out of the
gate, you could probably a chainless run
here just as fast as you could without
most racers like finding the edge and
not going over it was kind of the key.
That's the key in any downhill race,
yeah. Anywhere specifically on the track
you think, you know, the rock gardens,
anywhere that you can make a little bit
of time? Yeah, I think the rock gardens
for sure. I think you can maybe lose
more time than you can make if you mess
it up.
There's the main line, which is the
outside line to the right of the tree,
and then you have an inside line to the
left where you can kind of go inside and
then inside the next corner, too. It's a
little bit trickier because it's harder
to get that exit. It's going to be
interesting to see what riders choose
what. Most of them will choose the
outside, but there will some be some
people going inside.
How would you make time up there? Which
areas, anywhere specific? Um for me, I'd
say probably halfway down. I think it's
when you go over a bridge and it's kind
of like traversy, not flat enough, but
fast, but you kind of still want to make
sure to carry your speed. Think those
parts there to the bottom of you really
got to carry your speed. All the simple
bits actually is kind of where you want
to supposed to gain time.
>> Yeah. Overall, the track is pretty
tough, so you kind of want to be on it
the whole way down.
Honestly, I think some of that more
awkward stuff right before the Red Bull
ravine at the bottom, there's like some
steep switchbacks. And a couple little
awkward corners and if you kind of just
stall up a little bit in one of those
corners and you lose a quarter of a
second or something with how tight the
times usually are here, those are the
areas you kind of got to watch out for.
I think as it gets drier, it's going to
get looser, too. So, if you slide around
just a little bit and you kind of mess
one of those turns up,
it can kind of be the easy sections here
that can kind of surprise you if you're
not careful. And what about that stool
in the whoop section? Cuz the stool
wasn't there, was it last year? Yeah,
that's super new this year. It's really
hard. Do you jump in? Yeah, that's the
main goal is to carry enough speed
through the corners and then jump over
it and then land in the whoops. There is
an inside inside that you can do. I've
tried it and it's really hard. Aaron
made it look really easy, but I don't
think it's easy. Pretty big launch in
that first whoop, isn't it? It is, for
sure. It's and it's steep, too, and
short.
>> to get right.
>> Yeah, it's kicky.
After that, it's just flat out carrying
your speed to the finish line.
Good luck with that. Thank you.
The Tennessee National is proudly
presented by Dust Moto.
We all know the feeling of flow state on
a bike.
But imagine that same feeling downhill,
uphill, on flat ground, and with the
power of 42 [music] horses in your
hands.
The Dust Hightail is the dirt bike for
mountain bikers. It's quiet, low
maintenance, agile, and above all else,
fun.
Dust Hightail, coming this summer.
Well, great to hear from the racers
there, which I think we can [laughter]
We are the racers. We can include
ourselves in that. We're wearing the
bands. You know, I love this track.
Steep, fast, barely not a pedal stroke
on it, right? This it's all out. It is
all out.
>> that that's the right way to put it and
I think, you know, I kind of section
this track. I love that we have split
times here. The top really, really fast
and I think one of the things that stood
out to me is there's not a lot of ruts
and so you're really searching for
traction and the track hasn't been
figured out yet. There's people, you
know, in the pits still talking about do
you go inside into the rock garden,
outside into the rock garden? So, it's a
track that is it's good for racing
because you can make up time all the way
down. Yeah, and there are some
outrageous gaps being pulled up there.
It's phenomenal to see. And of course,
everyone racing here is trying to get
their hands on one of these phenomenal
trophies. Last year we had axes. Yes,
baby. I want that.
That's the sickest trophy I got, I
think.
Sick axe. This thing is dope.
>> This year we've gone for something
slightly safer, a Gibson Les Paul guitar
actually from Nashville just down the
road. Amazing trophy as used by Jimmy
Page. You can play one, right? Not as
well as Jimmy.
>> don't don't [laughter] put me me and
Jimmy are leagues we're worlds apart.
We're worlds apart.
>> All right, I'll give you that. I'll give
you that. Well, earlier in the week we
sent Aaron in to collect these prizes.
What's up, guys? We are here at Gibson
Guitars in Nashville, Tennessee today.
It is the big day. We get to pick up our
trophies for the Red Bull Tennessee
National that we're hosting at the bike
park here in about 2 weeks. So, super
cool to be partnered with Gibson and I'm
a bit of a fanboy, so pretty cool. Get
to go check out their whole place here
and pick these guitars up, so I can't
wait to see them.
All right, here's the
trophy for you.
I like that thing.
Gold top. Got to be gold.
Yeah. First place. Gold for first.
Let's go.
That was awesome. Thank you, guys. Yeah.
Absolutely. Killer.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Well, it's race day here now at the Red
Bull Tennessee National and it's been a
a big couple of days, Elliott, right?
Two days of practice, seeding yesterday.
What's been going on on the hill? Well,
I mean, as you know, last year we had
ton of weather. Rained during the race,
before race. This week, it's been same
condition. Sun's been out all week. I
talked to Ainslie Wulf and Mazie Lenae
just as they were going up for their
last practice run. They said, you know,
lines are the same. It's really just
about executing. I mean, yesterday we
saw a ton of mistakes. Ronan Dunne, Neko
Mulally, Neko Mulally, Neko Mulally,
Neko Mulally, Neko Mulally, Neko
Mulally, Neko Mulally, Neko
And you can make up time at each sector.
There was so much movement between each
one in the men and the women. So, it's
going to be a great race. Well, it is
indeed. The track is running fast. As
you even alluded to there, yesterday we
did have the riders against the clock in
seeding run. Let's have a look then at
what happened. Yeah. Well, I mean, I I
think Eleonora Farina just picked up
exactly where she left off, beating Anna
by 5 seconds. I know Anna said that she
had a a pretty chill run. She's going to
take off some time there. And then
obviously Kailey Skelton in third place,
the the three dominant women. But I
think to me, the interesting one is
Frida Rönning in fourth place. I mean,
just 16 years old on that Frameworks
Racing team. Multi-disciplined, comes
from kind of that XC background and
obviously the other Oscar sister,
Taylor, in fifth place. So, it's really
good to see these these women being able
to compete against this world-class
talent.
>> Always hard to read the results of
seeding. You never quite know who's done
what. Today though, it is race day.
Things will be different. I think it's
time we went racing at Windrock.
So, our first rider then, Anna Newkirk
from West Virginia, just 18 years old. A
great qualifier for her
on that Frameworks TRP team.
And already headed into this track. This
top section, Elliott, you've got to
carry speed for a big straight coming
up.
>> Yeah, that's right. I mean, this turn in
particular is one of the most difficult
on the entire track. Catch that edge,
but you have to get that exit good
because this section is so flat. You
have to carry your speed out of that
right-hander. You can see Anna just
drifting a little bit there. The surface
super slippery. It's been dry here all
week. 36.3
through that first split. Of course,
Zana is the benchmark for us. Many
lines, I would say, through that rock
section there. Yeah, definitely. It's
kind of the first big technical section
that the riders will have to navigate,
and I think right now we're kind of
seeing how slippery it is. You can see
the shiny bit. It's super dusty onto the
top of the track. You have to be really
easy on your brakes. Up onto that rock
there, and now as brave as you want to
be off this bridge. Big steep landing
for it. Lots of rocks. ZANA, OH, CASING
A LITTLE rock on there. Just over the
minute mark now.
In this section here, even though it
looks easy, that water, it's a spring,
natural spring that's been running off.
Roots are really slippery there, and I
think Zana, especially, really working
on this last end of the track. She had a
really good top split in her seeding
run, so she can clean up this bottom,
she'll be on pace. And we know that
fitness shouldn't be a problem for us
well. A competitive cross-country racer
with her sister, who's actually going to
be up coming in a few riders' time.
And a brilliant World Cup season for
her. Only finishing out of the top 10
once in the entire junior World Cup
season. So, amazing to see. That's
right. I mean, already taking a second
off of her seeding run, so getting a
good run here in the finals for Zana.
And just carrying as much pace as she
can. Two different lines through that
rock section there. She hooks it tight.
Yeah, un-weighting here, and this is
kind of you get a little bit of a
breath, and this coming into this last
little bit. Inside there, you can kind
of carry your speed, and it's really
just tucking, pumping, breathing all the
way to the finish. That's right. 2:21 at
the last split there. Riders getting
down towards the bottom now. Couple of
turns. We're going to go into this whoop
section now. Are they going to jump in?
Yes, she does. Double and then a triple
out if you can get it. And it's off the
brakes now. High-speed run all the way
to that finish line. A couple of big
drops coming. Get up into this last
left-hander over the Red Bull drop.
That's it. Get some PEDAL STROKES IN.
SO, HERE COMES ZANA LOGAR. SHE'S GOING
TO SET THE BENCHMARK FOR US. IT IS A
2:53.54.
That's your benchmark.
>> Yeah, great run from Zana taking 2
seconds off of her qualifier. And this
is that turn that I was talking about.
Get your brakes there. Really dive into
that left-hander before you pop up high.
So, our next rider then, Taylor
Ostgaard, from Washington. Actually
spends a lot of her time here at
Windrock Bike Park in Tennessee. Knows
this place well. And she's the older
sister of Eletha. Of course, who won
here last year.
Two of the sister pairings that we've
got in this women's final, and carrying
great pace up top here. Yeah, and that
was what we were talking about with
Zana, getting a little bit wide in that
right-hander, so she really had to fight
to get it back up high on that right.
But so good over the jumps. Actually,
Taylor just only .05 off of her sister
at the bottom. And up by a second at
split number one as well. Carrying great
pace through that rock section there. A
big hitter on the US Pro Downhill
series, this woman. Some big results
there. Spends less time overseas than
her sister. Incredible corner speed. I
mean, the traction that that she has,
using those hips to kind of get her turn
made, using that back end to kind of
steer. Really, really nice. You can see
why she's so good at this track.
Opting to keep the wheels on the ground
there, and losing a little bit of
that advantage. Less than half a second
now for her, but still very much in the
green. And the times, we know, will be
super tight on this high-speed and
relatively short track today.
>> Yeah, that's right. Diving into that
right-hander, it's another important one
to get back up, cuz it's slightly
uphill. Taylor not opting to do that
little gap. And also dropping down to
that lower berm. Not scrubbing off the
speed earlier, and trying to make that
turn across that camera. I think we will
see that line coming more and more. And
now it's red for her. Nearly a second
then behind for Taylor Ostgaard. And
here's that inside that we were talking
about. Zana opting for the outside.
Taylor shaving off a ton of distance
with that one. So, yeah, it's amazing to
see the different line choices up there.
Little puff of dust off the back wheel
there. The course hasn't been drier than
this all week. Hooks it tight into that
rock section. Looked absolutely
faultless through there. The next split
will be interesting.
>> Yeah, I mean, Taylor just so good at
carrying speed. Almost like her tires
are glued to the ground.
Yeah, you can absolutely see it. Pumping
where she needs to as well.
Yeah, I'm surprised that she's back on
the splits. The next ONE WILL TELL US
SHE'S UP NOW THEN BY OVER A SECOND. SO,
OSTGAARD FIRING BACK MID-RUN HERE.
Heading down towards this difficult
whoop section. You've got TO GET THAT
JUMP IN PERFECT. SHE DOES. AND CLEAN OUT
AS WELL. AMAZING pace through there.
>> And this is where she shined, making up
2 seconds to everyone except for her
sister, Eletha. So, they're expecting
her to put some really big time into our
current hot seat.
>> Here she comes then. Up and over THAT
LAST STEP UP. KEEPS IT LOW. TAYLOR
OSTGAARD GOES FASTEST BY 2 SECONDS.
2:51.54
NOW THE time to beat. That was such a
good run. I mean, incredible to see. The
track is so, so slippery, but I didn't
see like a a slid front tire, slid rear
tire. This is that rock garden, so she's
going to kind of come up a little bit
high, get her braking done, and then
dive kind of left. And then set up for
this right-hander. As soon as you come
off of that rock, you're trying to stay
off the brakes as much as you can.
Well, Reina Logar next. We saw her
sister first up now. 2:53 for her in
qualifying. Another woman who races a
lot in the Downhill Southeast Race
Series, the Pro Downhill Series here in
America. And another woman with
incredible pace, I would say, Elliot.
>> Yeah, really gets that left-hander good.
You can see her kind of use that
compression to make the last little bit
of her turn. Perfect around that
left-hander, so she'll have good speed
coming into this first flat section.
>> Yeah, didn't slide at all. You've got to
be clever on the brakes there. And she's
up by nearly a second at split number
one then. So, a massive RUN FOR REINA.
YEAH.
>> [laughter]
>> AND THAT WAS WILD DOWN THROUGH THAT ROCK
SECTION.
>> And that's what you need to do. That's
why this track is so difficult is
because you have to make your turns in
these really awkward positions
with no edge to turn on. Off that
difficult drop there. Hard on the brakes
a bit there. And oh, carries a great
line up high on that rock there as well.
So, amazing pace out there.
>> this is good. Perfect average speed
through these turns. And jumps deep out
there. And now it's nearly 2 and 1/2
seconds the advantage for Reina Logar.
So, bringing the heat here to the Red
Bull Tennessee National today.
>> And you can see her, she's just not kind
of stopping and starting. It's It's this
flow. It's It's such nice flow. Really
perfect on her breaking points. Breaking
early so that she can carry speed
through the turns. Yeah, seamless.
That's what we want to see. Absolutely.
Going down to that low catch berm as
well. Still not opting to keep it high
on that camera.
And the next split tells us she's nearly
3 seconds into the green now. Well,
Eletha Ostgaard will be at the top AND
WILL BE ABLE TO SEE THIS RUN. I like
that hopping to the first inside and
then going outside. That section is so
easy to make a mistake in. So, a little
bit of a safer line there for Reina. But
still on the gas down here. Keeping off
those brakes. Tight through that rock
section as well. I wonder if we'll see
the outside line coming at all today.
Yeah, taking a couple of cranks, getting
up high there. That is so important to
carry your speed. And now she'll be into
this stall wall
coming up soon. That's right. Another
big blind drop to go. Gets a pedal in
there as well. And it is literally off
the brakes. The advantage now to just
less than 2 seconds. But that's still on
a short track like this is a country
mile. You might need a TARDIS to catch
that back up.
>> Oh, cases a little bit. I mean, Taylor
made up 1.6 on her in this last sector
in seeding. So, she's not out of the
woods yet. So, going to be off the
brakes. Carrying as much speed as she
can around that big left-hand turn off
the Red Bull ravine. SHE COMES IN.
PERFECTLY OVER THAT DOUBLE. IT'S BEEN A
HECK OF A RUN FOR REINA LOGAR. AND SHE
GOES FASTEST BY .41 OF A SECOND. Losing
time in the lower sections. to beat.
Oh, what an amazing run from from Reina.
I mean, that top section is such a
masterclass.
And I mean, looking right here, look at
this. Breaks hard, gets up high, and
then just slides the back end around,
lets off the brakes. You don't see her
locking up the back tire. On those
rocks, exactly what you want to do.
Well, three to go here then at Windrock
Bike Park. And now it is the turn of the
US National Champion, the reigning
National Champion, Kailey Skelton. A
woman who actually won here in 2023. So,
knows the ins and outs of this place
well. Yeah, I mean, you can definitely
see the wind picking up. Opting to hop
out of there. This track is so difficult
cuz you want to be aggressive. Her
getting some pedals into there, but you
can
>> She's super aggressive up here, Elliot.
>> That's right. And insane scrub over
that. Getting those pedals in left,
right, and center up there. Let's see
what it's done to the clock. Well, she
finds herself in the red, but only by a
small margin. A lot of track left. And
carrying enormous pace through that rock
section. Yeah, I think
Kailey will get better as she goes down
the track.
Super attacking run here. I wonder how
that will pay dividends on this slippery
surface. Getting inside, hopping all the
way into the back side of that rock, so
that'll do good for her her speed coming
down that straight. What can she do off
this bridge? Sends it a little bit.
Pulls back some of that deficit then.
So, it's going the right way on the
clock for Kailey Skelton so far. Yeah,
and I would expect this to be one of the
sections that she makes up some time in.
One of those sections that requires a
lot of experience. You know, where do I
push? Where do I pump? What lines do I
take? Hopping into the back side of
that.
>> the double there. That'll give her a
little bit of pace further down as well.
Hard on the brakes there. Drops down to
that berm lower.
But very dynamic on the bike, Kailey
Skelton.
And now SHE GOES GREEN BY NEARLY A
SECOND. SO, THAT HARD WORK is paying off
for her. Yeah, really good. And her bike
looks really good. Opting to go inside.
That's that difficult part. So good
around that.
>> That was fast across that camber cuz
you've got to be on the brakes across
it. It's really, really difficult. Big
root right in the middle of it. You see
her tucking the elbow just to make it
around that tree. And looking like she
didn't brake for that rock section there
either. So Scouten, surely it's going to
be even further into the green at the
next split. Which line's she going to
take here? Yeah, and I like the way her
bike's set up. She's She's got it a
little bit softer. Dropping the heel,
she's getting a lot of braking done.
Split four, SHE'S UP BY 1.4 NOW. SO, A
BRILLIANT RUN THEN FOR KAILEY SCOUT.
REMEMBER, TWO RIDERS LEFT AT THE TOP.
Turns right now into this whoop section.
Sends it INTO THERE PERFECTLY. OH, FAST
THROUGH THERE AS WELL. GETS HER PEDALS
IN BEFORE this drop.
>> Yeah, she is going so good. Shaving off
time where she needs to. Shaving off
distance where she needs to into these
large left-hand, right-hand turns. SO,
THE THREE-TIME US NATIONAL CHAMPION
COMES DOWN TOWARDS THE LINE. SURELY
SHE'S GOT TO GO FASTEST. KAILEY SCOUT
TAKES THE LEAD. 2:48.72.
Nearly 3 seconds up. A massive run.
Yeah, that was incredible.
That was so good. I mean, a little
couple of mistakes out of the out of the
start, but then as soon as she got into
it, it was perfect. Look at this.
Dropping her heels down, gets so much
braking done there. Perfect kind of form
into that right-hander. And then she
goes out and gets the inside after this
little roll there. So, that was I think
the section where Kailey really was just
on fire. And again, this is another one
of those section opting to go low, below
the rock rather than up high. And you It
takes a lot of commitment, right? Like,
as soon as you dive into there, you
really have to be on it looking to the
exit. Shaving off some track though.
Anna Newkirk next then. From Salt Lake
City, actually. Spends a lot of time in
Switzerland on the Frameworks bike. And
a woman who finished twice second at
World Cup downhill races last year. So,
there's no argument with how fast she's
going to be.
DIDN'T JUMP THERE AND GOT A BIG KICK OFF
THAT ROCK. YOU CAN HEAR What is nice AND
HOW GOOD SHE'S GOING to be. Yeah, I
mean, that's one of those ones where
she's probably been jumping that all
week, but just maybe lost a little bit
of concentration there.
She would have definitely been jumping
it all week. Well, not too much damage
done. First time we've seen her inside,
and that's going to inside, inside. And
that's one of those turns right at the
bottom that you have to commit to. So,
it does shave off distance, but that
right-hander into that flatter section
is uh is what the crux is. Well, let's
see what the next split time will tell
us then. It looks super fast and direct
for me there. And again, carrying great
pace through there. Up on to that rock
as well.
>> Yeah, and you can see that Anna doesn't
quite have as much pace around these
some of these flatter turns. And
>> She's pulling up, it looks like. Three
in the red. I'm seeing if there's any
air in that. Yeah, I feel like something
I think Anna Newkirk has got a puncture.
A rear flat, is it?
>> Yeah.
Oh, what a shame for Newkirk then. Yeah,
I was wondering I wonder if it was I
wonder if it was the rock right at the
top.
It possibly could have been. Well, what
a shame for her then.
Yeah, she was fighting back.
Let's see if we can see where that
happened earlier.
>> Makes sense. Yeah, let's see this. Look
at the back tire here.
And maybe picking up a slow puncture
there.
>> Yeah, for sure.
Yeah, and as soon as that happens, I
mean, a lot of people are running the
Cush Core and and things like that now.
So,
you uh you won't see it maybe go all the
way. Oh, it's all the way low. Never
mind. That's it. So, Anna Newkirk
pulling off the track. Well, our number
one qualifier, last year's winner by a
massive margin, Eleonora Oscard. Can she
do it again? The signs are there that
she will. Been riding absolutely
brilliantly all week. And still,
unbelievably, a junior rider. Hops over
there, no problem for Oscard. Oh, man. I
mean, she got some pedal strokes in
right after that. Getting a pedal stroke
in everywhere. I mean, look at
Eleonora's bike. She runs a much stiffer
bike. So, that's going to allow her to
carry a ton of speed on these flat
sections, but it's so difficult to get
traction. And four wins in last year's
She's up by 0.37.
Then a small margin, but it is green for
her. And actually winning four wins in
the junior World Cup last year on her
way to second overall.
>> I mean, just watching her every single
part of the track she uses. She's
pushing down. She's pumping it. There's
no wasted energy, no wasted space here.
Every single inch of this track is being
used to generate speed. And she is, like
you say, so complete. Brilliant in the
air. Brilliant on the ground. Look at
that. Nearly 2 seconds up then. So, a
huge second sector for Eleonora Oscard.
AND THESE SECTIONS HERE WHISTLING down
through that steep shoot. That was
bonkers fast into that right-hander.
>> I mean, she's looks like she's so
experienced. You can just tell a
downhill rider, they'll pump and then
they'll chill. Like, these little micro
things, right? And she's There you see
that This is one of the first times
we've seen that inside to the outside
shaving off a ton of distance into that,
but it's so hard to get your braking
done. And so good ON THE BRAKES. 4.2 UP
THERE. THIS IS A HUGE RUN FROM ELEONORA
OSCARD. OH, THE ELITES AROUND THE world
are going TO BE SCRATCHING THEIR HEADS.
THEY'RE GOING TO WON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO
WITH HER WHEN SHE GOES UP NEXT YEAR.
>> I mean, I just don't know how she's
finding so much traction. This track is
so incredibly slippery. There's no
moisture here.
And she's so aggressive. Just bouncing
on THOSE ROCKS. BOUNCING OFF THEM AS
WELL. PUTTING THAT BIKE EXACTLY WHERE
she wants it then. Eleonora Oscard
showing us just what she's got here
today.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I mean, you can just tell
the way that she generates speed taking
the inside, inside there. Always
pedaling, always pumping.
And she's up 5.37.
Well, she can almost get off and have a
nap on the side of the track and still
win this one. Perfectly sends it into
the whoops. Gets the triple out.
Off this drop then, she's almost THERE.
SHE CAN ROLL TO THE LINE NOW. ELEONORA
OSCARD HAS DONE IT AGAIN. IT'S GOING TO
BE BACK-TO-BACK WINS FOR HER. JUST SIT
OFF THIS RED BULL RAVINE. THIS LAST
STRAIGHT TO GO. HERE COMES ELEONORA
OSCARD THEN. SHE WINS THE RED BULL
TENNESSEE NATIONAL BY A MASSIVE MARGIN.
2:42. Oscard does it again. Incredible.
>> Oh, what a run from Eleonora. I mean,
that was a absolute masterclass. Pumping
where she needed to. Just chilling kind
of where she needed to. I know she
doesn't feel like that, but watching
watching her ride is just insane.
Look at this. What Look at how she does
the back end. Places it. Hops it all the
way down into that turn. That turn is so
incredibly slippery. Look at this.
Pops down. Turns within a maybe a a 2 ft
of track. Hops all the way into the
backside of this rock. And even jumps up
on that to get more speed off it. Like,
that is that is what you see from you
know, these world-class athletes.
Eleonora just in a league of her own
here.
>> Absolutely. 6 seconds then up on Kailey
Scout. Rachel Atherton comes in third.
Eleonora's sister in fourth. And Zana
Longa in fifth. Two pairs of sisters in
the top five. Incredible.
>> I mean, they're riding so good. I mean,
it shows the amount of talent that is
here. I mean, and the times are really
tight. We you know, from second all the
way down to sixth, only a 6-second gap.
So, good to see everyone have a good
run. And I mean, golly, that was an
insane an insane race.
And now they are giving those incredible
Les Paul Gibson guitars from the factory
just down the road in Nashville.
Eleonora Oscard, a two-time Red Bull
Tennessee National Champion.
Let's hear from the winner now.
The pressure was
actually not as bad as I thought it was
going to be with trying to do the
back-to-back. But, it's kind of my home
mountain, so I kind of have that little
bit of an unfair advantage. I will own
it.
But, at the same time, just being like,
it's my first race of the season. Get
all the cobwebs off. Get ready for the
World Cup season. Is my main goal with
this race. Have all my family around.
Have Aaron and Lauren put on this
amazing race. Just being comfortable is
a big thing starting the season with.
So, I'm really just stoked on that. I'm
going to have to do some lessons cuz I
have no idea how to play. Like, they
were trying to do a solo on the podium.
I have no idea.
This year, I'm just really going for
consistency. And I'm stoked that I can
start it off right here. And just going
to keep going with it throughout the
season.
And Elliot, what happened in men's
seeding yesterday? I couldn't help but
notice a certain name at the top. Well,
I mean, good grief. The dude in first
place beat Luca by half a second. But,
the the story that doesn't really get
told is that he didn't have the best
first split. So, he's got another second
in him at the top. And then, you know,
Dylan Maples. Good to see him up there.
New team in third place. I know that we
had Ronan Dunn make a bit of a mistake
at the bottom. Same with Ryan Pinkerton.
But, Cole Suetos, fourth place. Really,
really nice. Really nice bottom for him.
Another rider that's got a little bit to
clean up at the top. And then, Dante
Silva picking up where he left off last
year. Looked really good in practice.
Really enjoying it. And uh I think he's
ready for a a good result here. But, I
think again,
it's not it's not decided yet. I think
the results are going to be shuffled up,
and we're going to see some some big
surprises.
>> It is the USA season opener. The
Americans are going to want to win this.
There's going to be a battle royal here
tonight. That is for sure. And now,
we're about to go racing at Windrock.
Well, Luca Shaw
opening things up for us then from Long
Island in New York. Fairly unusual place
for a downhill mountain biker to come
from, I would say. Oh, man. There's tons
of rocks up there. So, he's going to be
no stranger to that. Getting up high
there. Really nice through that. I think
if you can get back out to that
left-hander as well. Sliding a little
bit there is going to do a little bit to
his speed. He's looking for under 33 for
this first split. See if he's on pace.
>> And we do know that he comes in. Let's
have a look at this first split. It is
under 33. So, definitely things going
well for Dedora.
No benchmark for him yet, of course,
first rider we're seeing on track today.
Yeah, I think that's a hit that little
gap really fast through there. Doesn't
go over the rock. There's a gap that you
can do over to the over the rock on the
left-hand side. And we know
it's that turn out that he's coming in
here with pace. Won a downhill Southeast
race just 2 weeks ago. Jumps clean over
those rocks off that bridge there. A
frightening prospect, I would say,
Elliot. It's completely blind.
>> Yeah, exactly. I mean, 1.5 up on his
seeding time. So, Lucas having a better
run than he did in seeding. Really
smooth here. Couple little mistakes.
Couple little lost traction, but he
he'll be on pace so far for a better
run. Directly down to that low berm as
well there. But, pumping everywhere.
Working each part of this track as much
as he can. It's physical, that's for
sure. Going to stay high on this camber
there. Good pace across there. It's so
slippery and you've got to be on the
brakes.
>> You have to be so patient hopping all
the way over that rock garden. Another
2.6 up in his seeding time. So, a much
better run for him in finals.
>> And he really opened up that rock
garden, didn't he? Jumping out of it
like that. So, yeah, an incredible run
here then so far for Lucas Tedora, 18
years old.
Through the last split on track. Goes up
high over that rock there. Going to
carry a lot of pace. Oh, into this whoop
section. Big triple out. Absolute
perfection through there. Scrubs off
that drop as well.
>> Oh, it's such a good style. I mean,
Lucas riding so good this year. He is
absolutely This has been an incredible
run from him then. Here he comes,
Tedora. GOES ACROSS THE LINE. 2:30 the
time to beat.
A great run there.
I mean, this is that top section. Gets a
pedal stroke out of there.
Smooth into this left-hander. I mean,
Lucas is just riding good. Bike working
really good for him. See him kind of
using that back end steering with the
back end. Slides a little bit there, but
you don't want to give it up.
Austin Dooley then. Well, great to see
him back on the start line here. Broke
his pelvis at this race 12 months ago.
So, a big recovery from him though. I
mean, and dude, Austin's just had some
great results. I mean, second at
National Champs in '24. I mean, 13th at
Worlds in '24. RIDING REALLY GOOD.
SLIDING [screaming] OUT THERE. SUPER
FAST INTO THAT LONG LEFT THERE. YEAH,
and second second to Dakota Norton here
as well a few years ago. Oh, he didn't
even take off over that tabletop THERE
AND HE'S UP BY OVER HALF a second then.
So, Dooley on the move here today. And
really just staying on the ground. Not
opting to kind of hop or do any gaps or
anything in that rock garden. That's
that double that we were talking about,
which is probably going to see him hop.
Left going low.
There is a lily pad rock there you can
take if you want to, BUT AT THE PACE
DOOLEY WENT THROUGH THERE, I'm not sure
it would be an option. Surely going to
send it way PAST THE ROCKS OFF HERE. HE
DOES. Nearly a second into the green
now. Green now for Austin Dooley then.
Austin is just putting his tires exactly
where he needs to. That section you have
to take a ton of risk. He needed to do
that because you need to carry speed up
and around that left-hander. But, watch
Austin's tires. You don't see much roost
or anything coming off of them. Really
perfect on the brakes. Not locking the
back tire up where he doesn't need to.
Hopping into these rollers. Yeah,
absolutely smooth, isn't it? You're
absolutely right there and now HE'S INTO
THE GREEN BY OVER A SECOND. SO, DOOLEY
doing everything right here. Oh, that's
perfect.
>> fast across there as well. That seamless
kind of style that we're looking for.
You don't see him really stalling that
bike anywhere. No, I mean, and Austin's
one of those riders where you don't see
him kind of squaring off the turns.
Really rounding out all of these turns.
Carrying his speed. He knows what to do.
The downhill is about the high average
speed everywhere. Just letting that
momentum, yeah. Keeping that average
speed up all the way down here. Still
over a second into the green then.
Sets up high there. Heading down towards
these big whoop sections. Jumps in.
Little bit off ON THE TAKEOFF. MANAGES
TO HOLD IT. MANUALS OUT. Super fast for
Dooley through there.
>> Yeah, a little bump jump in this.
Perfect run so far. I mean, this is a
master class.
Haven't seen him do anything wrong then.
So, DOOLEY IS GOING TO GO FASTEST. HERE
HE COMES. PERFECT UP OVER THAT LAST
JUMP. 1.192.
29 TO BEAT. ANY TIME UNDER the 2:30 mark
will take some beating today. AUSTIN
DOOLEY LAYS one down at Red Bull
Tennessee National.
>> Yeah, I mean, pretty much every sector
on the track a much better time than he
had.
And this is
gets good brakes and then he uses the
compression actually to finish his
braking and then turn up high. But, just
so micromanaging all of these uh
compressions so well. You saw him kind
of hop into that. Put his back tire
exactly where he needs to. Just using
the compressions on the track so well.
And you really have to because or else
you can't can't get traction.
Well, this man will be throwing the
kitchen sink at it. Nigh is on track,
the Intense Factory Racing rider from
Bakersfield in California.
And he won a downhill Southeast race
actually last year. Interestingly,
beating Aaron Gwin on his way of doing
so. So, he does have some pace. Find a
bit of a slide into that big left.
Pedals out of it. Yeah, I mean, Nate's
been riding really smooth all week. Got
to see him, talk to him, and he was just
talking about how much he wants to stay
smooth.
And he's got a bit of work to do then.
Nearly a second back at split number
one.
That's quite a margin, Elliot, before
that first split.
>> Yeah, you can see Nate opting for a
little bit softer softer bike setup,
which is going to give him better
traction on sections like that, but the
rock gardens are going to be a little
bit harder for him.
But, look how physically he's all over
that bike, backwards and forwards.
Pumping where he can.
Absolute accuracy out there though, but
still losing time to Austin Dooley.
Stays high on that camber. Trying to
shave a little bit off. Probably not as
quick down there either as Dooley was.
>> No, I mean, I think that that's kind of
the difference that we're seeing is like
Austin getting on the backsides of a lot
of these rollers, a lot of the rock
gardens. This is that outside. So, once
you go left, you can hop up high, go
across the line, and then double over.
So,
really really nice line from there.
>> was absolutely insane. It hasn't helped
him though. Over 2 seconds back now. The
first rider, Elliot, that we've actually
seen take that higher camber line. Maybe
it's not going to work. Yeah, I mean, if
you take the the right line down the
hill, you can just carry so much speed
in and you just brake really hard. If
you're taking that outside, which we saw
which we saw Nate take, you're really
kind of micromanaging the off camber and
trying not to brake and then it's a
little bit nibbly on the way out.
Yeah, jumps through out that rock turn
as well.
Oh, gets a slide on there. You can see
by the bike's moving about just how
treacherous, I would say, this surface
is. We know it's super super slippery
today. 2.6
>> Oh, I like that inside. I like that.
Dude, THAT WAS INSANE. STILL
GETS THE JUMP INTO THE WHOOPS. Bad lines
there then.
Nate Kitchen bringing some creativity to
this run. But, the clock telling a
different story for him, unfortunately.
He's looked good top to bottom.
So, Kitchen crosses THE LINE AND GOES IN
a fifth place. 2.71 off a 2:31.8.
Almost the exact same time as his
seeding. So,
probably some stuff on on that run that
he's proud of and probably some of it
that he uh he'd like to clean up.
Let's see. This is that inside. I
believe coming into that rock garden.
So, you really have to turn tight and
then over these roots you can just see
kind of tires are sliding a little bit
and then you have this off camber, but
you do get a straighter run into this
double, which I think a lot of the
riders are trying to pop that
from the outside. Is it that exit? Yeah.
>> was insane. That was
really really nice. And that bump jump
as well.
Perfect run
through there from Kitchen.
Well, a massive day then for rider
Lawrence. Riding for Mondraker bikes.
His first ever elite race, this man.
The Pro Downhill 17 to 18 champion.
And two top four. A little mistake
there. Gets a foot off at the top.
>> Well, there's a there's a high line
there, but a lot of people aren't taking
it because of exactly that. Where you it
messes up that right-hander, which is
really the important one. So, we'll see
what it does to his split. But, not
getting that right-hander. And he's back
by nearly a second. Definitely uh can
turn that around. Yeah, getting that
hop.
>> good though, Elliot, is it, to make a
mistake at the top of your run?
>> Once you're there, I mean, once you make
a mistake there, you really almost
sometimes it locks you in even more
because you have to. Hopping over little
pre-hop there. Is that gap that WE'VE
BEEN TALKING ABOUT? GETS IN BIG TROUBLE.
GOES OVER THE FRONT. AND THAT DROP THERE
ONTO THAT LILY PAD rock is probably the
most technical move on the mountain. IT
IS ABSOLUTELY INSANE. AND IT WORKS FOR
HIM THERE. NOW, THE RISKY PULLS BACK A
LITTLE BIT OF TIME THERE, ELLIOT. YEAH,
I mean, Noster wants to be getting these
really difficult lines, but just not
quite able able to link them, execute
them where he wants. So, if he can get
back in, lock back in, and execute his
run the way that he's practiced it,
he'll be on for a good result.
>> And he is the US Pro Downhill Series
champion for the 17 TO 18. CAGUIRA GETS
THAT DOUBLE AS WELL OFF THERE.
AND NO, IT DOESN'T DO HIM ANY FAVORS
THOUGH. 1.76
back now.
>> Oh, super fast into there. Hopping over
the root. Getting a little bit hung up
there. I think, you know, rider just the
the I don't know, the flow, kind of the
where he's breaking, where he's carrying
speed is maybe a little bit of off
timing. You can see him just sliding
right where he doesn't want to be. Picks
that hits that rock on the exit of that
turn there, and jumps out of there as
well. Son of Rider Lawrence IS ACTUALLY
JEREMY MCGRATH'S MECHANICAL THROUGH HIS
CAREER and nearly losing the back end
OFF THAT ROCK THERE. INCREDIBLE CONTROL
THEN FROM RIDER LAWRENCE. OH, OVER 2
SECONDS BACK NOW. OH, I haven't seen
that hopping off all the way over. AND
JUMPS IN AS WELL. This guy, he's so
skilled. I mean, he's he's downhill
junior downhill, sorry, dual slalom
national champion, fifth at Mount Saint
Anne junior World Cup last year. So, he
is super super fast.
>> He's a big hair, comes from a BMX
background as well. He loves THESE
JUMPS. SO, RIDER LAWRENCE THEN COMES
DOWN TO THE LINE AND GOES IN A FOURTH
PLACE AT 2:31.25
FOR HIM. 2 seconds into the red at the
end.
>> Yeah, I mean, that's one of those runs
where
he'll actually take a lot of confidence
from that because he'll kind of look at
his runs back. He'll look at his his
probably his GoPro, look at the split
times, and um know that there's so much
more time to be made up there. Just
popping a foot off there.
And this is that gap. You can just see
watch his back end slide right off of
there.
Oh, to hold that in is incredible. So,
Rider going to have a good season, I
think, this year. And that hop is crazy.
I haven't seen anyone else do that. To
be able to hop out of there, get on the
brakes quick enough, and then into the
whoop section.
>> at the style he does it with as well.
>> so good. So good.
>> Well, from one stylish American to
another, Ryan Pinkerton, another
Californian. A great qualifier for him
as well. What run can Ryan Pinkerton do
then? Been doing big things on the World
Cup circuit. Yeah, and I mean, he in his
seeding was first at the fourth split
before an off track in that whoop
section. So, he is actually on pace for
a win if he can clean his seeding run up
and execute what he knows he can
execute.
>> The speed is there for the current the
reigning US NATIONAL CHAMPION. AND HE
GOES GREEN AT THAT FIRST SPLIT AND
CARRIES PHENOMENAL PACE INTO THAT ROCK
GARDEN THERE. YEAH, frightening the
speed you're coming at it because
there's no getting rid of it once you're
in there.
This is such a nice run. Again, a rider
THAT HAS SO MUCH BRAKING SKILL HOPPING
over that.
>> AND THE CONTROL HE LILY PAD ACROSS THERE
SO PERFECTLY. DIDN'T GET SENT OVER THE
FRONT LIKE RIDER LAWRENCE. AND NOW IT
GOES GREEN. AMAZING RIDER, NEARLY A
SECOND then for him into the green. And
this is that section. This is one of the
quote unquote easiest sections, but you
can see how much pace he carries down
through there. Skims the edge of that
rock, gives him a little bit more space
into that right hander there. And these
margin these tiny margins are what ADDS
UP. WHEN THE TIMES ARE THIS TIGHT, TAKES
THAT LOW LINE THERE. YEAH, I mean, he's
just carrying so much speed. Even the
easy section, he's carrying so MUCH
SPEED.
>> MASSIVE, 2 SECONDS UP NOW THEN. SO,
PINKERTON IS ABSOLUTELY ON ONE. OH,
THERE HE GOES DOWN. OH, HE PINCHED UP
AGAINST THAT TREE ON THE WAY IN, and I
think it may have just set him a little
bit lower on that camber.
>> Well, you tuck your elbow in and it
completely upsets your body position.
There's a route that we can't see on the
other side of that rock. And it's so off
camber. That section is so incredibly
awkward. It's so difficult. So,
Pinky's just trying to push. That was
really the last section that he really
needed to execute before the finish, but
But you if you're going to win a day,
Elliot, we know the margins are going to
be insanely tight. It's ultra fast. 2
and 1/2 minutes of track only.
Yeah, doing everything right, but yeah,
paying the price just on, you know,
it is a difficult camber that.
>> So difficult. That is
>> speed they come into it, they've got to
try and break across it is bonkers.
>> Yeah, because you're seeing everyone
tuck an elbow because on the back side
of that rock, you maybe have 2 ft of um
of track to deal with, and it drops off
into kind of the normal bike park.
So awkward. So
a difficult day for Ryan Pinkerton. He
was
absolutely on fire though. He can at
least take that away.
>> and I mean, Ryan was looking so good
then hopping up high over that over that
rock, getting a really nice entry in,
you know, micromanaging that rock garden
really really well. He was just riding
so good until this mistake. See what
happened, gets a little bit outside, and
then just the butt gets hit on the tree,
hops out, and that just little just that
little bit. Margins.
>> Just a little bit of body body English,
and he goes down.
Okay, well, from Whistler in British
Columbia, the Canadian, Mikey Della
Salla. Great qualifier for him. Let's
see what he can do then in this finals
run.
>> Yeah, Mikey riding so good. He's spent a
lot of time training in Laguna.
>> Oh, GETS THAT HIGH LINE. WAY UP HIGH.
SO, THAT was what Rider Lawrence was
trying to do. He's going to have so much
speed coming into this flat section.
Let's see what he does to his first
split.
>> And scrubbing hard over there, so that
should drive Della Salla onto this long
straight AND GIVE HIM A GREAT FIRST
SPLIT, AND IT DOES. JUST .28 off then.
Yeah, and Mikey's been, you know, on
this Frameworks team riding with Nico
and Asa Aaron. So much pace on him. Goes
low of the rock.
Executes well, and then takes the
inside. Yeah.
>> Shaved
>> Shaved off a lot of track there. Yeah,
Mikey, I mean, shaving off a ton of
time. Different lines for him. And fast
through there and keeps it to under a
second into the red then. So, still very
much in touch.
But it's Austin Dooley, remember,
leading at THE BOTTOM. A PHENOMENAL RUN
FOR THAT MAN. OH, OVER THAT ROCK THERE
as well. And Mikey, you can see his bike
really like holding him up. Makes it
really easy. Makes or makes it a lot
easier to navigate these rock gardens
and carry speed through the cambers, but
much more difficult on all of this super
slippery off camber stuff. And pulls
back a little bit of time then. Well,
what's he going to do on this camber?
Perhaps a little slower, and perfect
though. Carried great speed across there
and through that turn as well.
>> Yeah, you could see him hop over the
rock to try to get his wheels back on
the ground, get some braking in. Really
pumping through there, opening up the
turns. Oh, this is a really nice lower
split for Mikey.
>> He's doing nothing wrong here. What's
the clock GOING TO TELL US THEN? Which
lines he going to take as we head down
to that split line as well. Yeah, and
Mikey had a great He had a really good
bottom in his seeding. So, can he do it
again? Oh, again. CLOSING UP, JUST 39
HUNDREDTHS NOW THEN.
Lays into THAT BIG LEFT HANDER, SCRUBS
INTO THE WHOOPS. HE'S COMING so fast.
>> Oh, that was one of the best whoop
sections we've seen. Scrubbing in,
getting a really low over there, really
low over the tabletop.
So, HERE HE COMES THEN, MIKEY DELLA
SALLA, THE CANADIAN. IT'S BEEN A
SCORCHING RUN TOP TO BOTTOM. CAN HE MAKE
IT RED TO GREEN? HE GOES INTO THIRD
PLACE. 9 hundredths off only at the line
at 2:29.26.
He can be happy with that one.
>> Yeah, I mean, Mikey. It was kind of the
same style of run that we saw from him
in seeding. Just slowly generating time.
I was talking to Nico, his team manager,
and he uh he was telling me that this
year he's really been training. So,
watch what he does. Breaks right here.
See that back wheel lock up. And then
somehow gets all the way up high. That
opens up that first right hander so
much. There's nothing on the exit of it.
And then again,
able to get his wheels back on the
ground and then pop out in that right.
Really really nice run by Mikey.
Okay, well, next up then is Dante Silva.
Just four riders left to drop after this
man from Chula Vista in California on
THE INTENSE BIKE. AH, THERE IT GOES.
WELL, THAT WAS SHORT AND SWEET. It is
over. And showing us just how slippery
that surface is. The front pushing there
Elliot.
>> Yeah, I mean, it's not really even a
section you kind of think about much,
but
>> No,
that's the problem.
>> Yeah, exactly. I mean, he was probably
already it's it's one of those things
you're already kind of thinking about
the next little section. There is a rock
garden that you can't see on the back
side of that. And so, kind of just
unweighted, and it's flat there. I mean,
that really isn't indicative of the
whole track. There's not much to hold
you in here, but you have to push into
all of this stuff so much.
>> Yeah, real shame for him then.
Pro Downhill Series champion. As we
said,
doing some big things on the World Cup
circuit as well.
>> Yeah, I mean, amazing result for him at
Lake Placid last year. Only
doing one World Cup last year. And now
he's keeping them honest on those split
times.
>> Yeah.
>> The consistent 12 [laughter] seconds
back. I know. Everything goes through
your head where you're just like, do I
go? Like, I know I'm not going to win,
but then I might as well. I came all the
way out here. I might as well put in a
good run, see what I was going to be
able to do.
See where my splits are at.
Taking that outside. This Yeah, didn't
get the double out. I'm curious which of
those two lines is faster, actually.
>> Yeah, yeah. Yeah, I think it they're so
different. And that really shows the
caliber of track that we have here at
the Red Bull Tennessee National that
we're seeing the top athletes take
different lines. I think by this time
usually you will see a track get figured
out. You know, everyone kind of being on
the same line, but almost every single
rider taking a different line, showing,
you know, kind of personality, what
different options they they have. I
mean, you know, it's Aaron Gwin's bike
park. It's Aaron Gwin's race. The track
is always going to be something special
when that man's involved. And of course,
he is the fastest qualifier. He is yet
to drop. He's never won the Red Bull
Tennessee National, either. There's that
inside. I like that. I like it. I would
love it if I
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, right.
>> could be able to do it. Even more
incredibly difficult.
>> what I would be on. That's what I would
be on. Mad. You Yeah. I'll give you
that, Elliot.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay, well, Dante Silva.
It's been a good run, actually, right on
the pace. Unfortunately, that crash at
the top seen him cross the line 13.6
into the red.
A day Dante would rather forget, I
think. Yeah, that'll be
give him some confidence going into next
weekend. Let's see what happens here.
Uh just totally, I think maybe just
slightly outside of the main line. Maybe
got into some of the little gravel baby
heads and you would just immediately
lose traction.
Dante getting back going and he'll be uh
racing again soon.
Well, Cole Suaitous
from Tennessee now residing here working
on this bike park as well a lot so he
knows THIS TRACK WELL.
AND I expected an all-out run from this
man.
Yeah, I mean Cole one of the track
builders here. I mean and he's done so
well over the years at the Nationals, at
the at the World Cups. I mean he is such
a strong rider perfect kind of body
position that box position on the bike.
What's he done at split number one then?
Well, nearly a second off but still in
touch a lot of track between here and
the finish line for him. Yeah, on that
Zenoni Factory Racing. Let's see what he
can do through this. Does he opt for the
gap? Doesn't. Goes low but that was
really nice using that to kind of allow
him to get the traction they need to to
go back up high going a little bit
further inside in the rock garden. And
to lily pad that rock comes with
enormous risk. He has lost a little bit
of time there though. Over the second
mark now then for Suaitous.
Oh. And you don't see you don't see Cole
kind of pedaling everywhere. You're
really using the terrain to generate
speed. You can see him going forward to
back on the bike pumping where he needs
to.
Keeping a lot of traction not really
messing up too much getting that pop.
Yeah, gets that high line and that
double out and it does pull him some
time back then. So, JUST OVER HALF A
SECOND OFF NOW. HE'S BACK IN CONTENTION
HERE ELLIOT. Inside there but somehow
keeping a ton of speed just stands up
tall making themselves thin. Insider
gets a good few hard pedal strokes there
as well. Yeah, this is a really one of
those riders that doesn't look like he's
really super aggressive but he is going
so fast.
>> Dude, he is absolutely on the move.
Austin Dooley will be sweating watching
this one. Precise and perfect OFF THAT
ROCK AS WELL. Getting better and better
as he goes down the track. I totally
agree with you. And the next split oh A
LITTLE BIT MORE TIME towards Austin
Dooley. Oh, so good around that left.
Doesn't get hung up. It's so difficult
that that left is so flat. Playing
through the whoop section. So, now it's
just OFF THE BRAKES LETTING ROLL ALL THE
WAY DOWN. TRYING TO SCRUB HARD OFF THIS
RED BULL RAVINE. THE TOP SPEED OF THESE
GUYS. HERE HE COMES THEN. IT'S BEEN A
MAGNIFICENT RUN FROM COLE SUAITOUS. IS
HE GOING TO BE FIRST, SECOND? WHERE'S HE
GOING TO GO? HE GOES INTO SECOND PLACE.
4,000THS OFF ONLY. INSANE MARGIN.
2:29.18.
DOOLEY over to congratulate him. It
doesn't get any closer than that. That
was incredible. I mean I feel like it
was so much of it was that left hander
before the whoops. That was crazy good.
I mean Cole
using every inch of the track. You see
him coming into these turns really high
exiting high, you know, all using every
kind of compression to get pumped. Watch
as he comes down here. Makes his turn up
high. Pumps. Hops in to the very right
of that rock. You don't see him come off
that tall part of the diving board. So,
Cole really knows this track super well
and using it to his advantage.
Well, a big day for this man then. One
of the first times out on the for the
Pivot Factory Racing team at Dylan
Maples on track.
And a man who can brilliant World Cup
results for him last year taking a
fourth in Val di Sole one of the fastest
World Cup races there is. Yeah, that was
amazing that first little straight.
That's exactly what we want to see low
high kind of a little bit of slide in
that left hander but Dylan talking about
how precise this bike is. And less than
half a second off. So, taking it to
Dooley then. He's absolutely on fire
here.
The margin's tiny here on this track
today. Yeah, and it does take a long
time to get used to a new bike. Let's
see what he does. Everyone a lot of
people opting for that low line there.
Allows you to get up high with a little
bit of better entry into the rock
section. Split two coming up then. Oh,
loses a little bit of time there. Still
in touch I would say though.
>> Yeah, I mean Austin had a crazy good
rock section. We just saw him. It made
it look so smooth.
Oh, gets a slide on there. This surface
is breaking up. Just 22 years old this
man. Yeah, I mean and if you try just to
use a little bit take a little bit too
much speed. OH, GETS THE LOW AND AND THE
GAP. Incredible to see that. The only
rider WE'VE SEEN DO THAT AND LOOK IT'S
WORKED FOR HIM. That line I think is so
good. That's exactly what you need to
do. So much speed into that section
we've seen cause so many problems. Sixth
in last year's World Championships as
well. Oh, gets those pedal STROKES IN AS
WELL. GAP TO THE SIDE OF THAT. YEAH,
DIDN'T BOTHER WITH THAT ROCK TAKE off
there.
Oh, looking for the margins everywhere
they can these riders. A centimeter
counts at this level. Yeah, Dylan really
coming into this uh lower section coming
into his own on this lower part of the
track. Yeah, he is. Gets a few more
pedal strokes IN THERE AS WELL.
>> [laughter]
>> HE'S PULLING BACK TIME. He's in touch.
So, Dooley will be looking UP THE TRACK
NOW.
HERE COMES DYLAN MAPLES. WHAT'S HE GOING
TO DO ON THIS LAST SECTION? CAN HE FIND
A QUARTER OF A SECOND? YEAH, able to
scrub that stall wall more than we've
seen almost anyone. PEDALS AT THE RED
BULL RAVINE AND MAPLES NOW TUCKING
UP OVER THIS LAST JUMP. HERE COMES DYLAN
MAPLES AND HE GOES INTO FOURTH JUST .34
off under the 2:30 mark. A great run for
the Californian.
Great run from Dylan. I mean to be able
to pull that back from being .9 at the
top.
Can see Dylan. This is that gap opting
to kind of pre-hop in. Pretty flat
landing there so that'll give him a
little bit more speed on that uphill.
Pumping in hopping the entire rock
garden. This is where Dylan shined on
this run was this lower lower split and
that was how it was all day all weekend
long. Well, two Americans left to drop
and two of the biggest dogs in the sport
of downhill. This man the world number
three from last year third overall in
last year's World Cup. I'm not sure
we've ever seen Loic Bruni riding better
than he is now Elliot.
>> Yeah, I mean you can just tell Loic oh
slides out a little bit. I was just
about to say you can you can see him he
barely slides. I mean this section he
put in half a second into everyone in
seeding. So, I'm interested to see what
he can do.
Yeah, oh look at that. He's still even
with that mistake only .07 down. 700ths.
He really pedaled hard to get back up to
pace then. And Loic Bruni will be
pulling on all that experience NOW.
PRE-JUMPED OVER THERE. SKATES DOWN
THERE. GETS THE LILY PAD PERFECTLY AS
WELL. YOU DON'T SEE IT DONE ANY BETTER
THAN THAT ELLIOT. SO FAST. I mean Loic I
mean similar to Austin JUST PERFECT
KEEPING TRACTION. LOOK AT THE LINE. HE'S
GREEN BUT LOOK AT THE LINE HE TOOK OFF
THAT BRIDGE. FULL COMMITMENT TO JUMP
OVER THAT ROCK ON THE RIDER'S LEFT.
>> can tell he has to kind of micromanage
the traction so much, you know, keeping
that body position not moving around a
lot. That's not going to that's going to
make sure the bike doesn't get upset.
Inside to outside getting tons of
braking into that compression. Hops out.
Hops again.
>> GAP AS WELL FROM THAT LOW LINE.
SO, THIS IS PHENOMENAL STUFF. HE'S UP BY
NEARLY A SECOND NOW THEN LOIC BRUNI. OH,
PUTTING ONE TOGETHER HERE TODAY AT
WINDROCK. THIS IS OH, DOUBLES OUT. WOW,
WOW, WOW. NO, NO, NO. OH, AND HE STALLS
JUST LIKE THAT. IT'S OVER FOR SURE. WOW,
WOW, WOW. WHAT WENT wrong there? Oh, he
he was trying to normally on the back
side of that rock you hop into the to
the bike park and he was trying to hop
from that soft part from that loamy bit
all the way into that next turn and just
had a little bit more speed than he was
used to. Couldn't get the braking done.
Well, there is time left on this track
as we watch Loic Bruni make his way
down. So close but so far and there's
still one rider left at the top of this
mountain. Like you said, I mean it's
insane to see how much time there but
Loic you have to ride this track. You
know, he obviously looks aggressive. He
looks fast but like I said you don't see
him moving around on the bike a lot.
It's not one of those tracks where
you're all over the place. You almost
have to be as still as possible because
any movement is going to make you lose
traction.
>> Yeah. You're right.
>> [laughter]
>> Well, Loic well, he didn't have too far
to come then living just over the border
in North Carolina. And this is that
first mistake that we saw
right there. Trying to pump into it. You
know, you want to push in to get speed
but there's nothing to hold you. Getting
his braking done. That's how you know
like I said, you don't see the back tire
locking up even though he's braking so
incredibly hard. You micromanage all of
the traction.
That is what it takes to do
to to have a time like that but I mean
right at the very end that section is so
difficult. Well, Aaron Gwin and yet to
win the Red Bull Tennessee National Air
Surgeon Aaron Gwin back on the speed
that saw him take all those World Cup
wins making history all the way through
his career. New team and he is
absolutely flying again this year with
that fourth at Red Bull Hardline
Tasmania.
Yeah, just completely locked in. You
don't see him sliding around, you know,
high into these turns high out. Perfect
over that little table top.
>> That's right. The second most successful
WORLD CUP RACER OF ALL TIME FINDS
HIMSELF JUST A TENTH OFF AT SPLIT ONE
AND ALMOST TURNING DOWN THOSE ROCKS.
TURNING ON THE ROCKS. That's crazy.
>> was crazy.
>> Hopping off of that last one all the way
over to the left inside there shaving us
as much distance as he can. And he goes
FOR THE LILY PAD PERFECT ACROSS THERE
FOR AARON GWIN THERE. AND THEN INSIDE.
UNBELIEVABLE RIDING FROM HIM. EVERYWHERE
he can take off distance he is. SPLIT
WHAT'S IT GOING TO BE SCREEN?
[screaming]
OH, TAKING MASSIVE RISKS AS WELL.
JUMPING RIGHT TO THE SIDE OF THE TRACK.
>> A LITTLE BIT
>> 701 THIS IS INSANE UNBELIEVABLE.
>> A LITTLE BIT unsettled there but he was
locked back in high. This the lines that
he takes are so incredibly precise going
low, going high.
This is unbelievable vintage AARON GWIN
THEN. SO FAST, SO PRECISE. ABSOLUTELY
BACK TO HIS BEST NOW 2.2 UP. THIS IS
MASSIVE END FROM THE GWINSTER.
OH, WE HAVEN'T SEEN HIM RIDE LIKE THIS
AND DOWN HE GOES LIKE A HOMESICK MOLE.
GWIN CRASHES OUT OF THE RED BULL
TENNESSEE NATIONAL. 2 SECONDS UP HELIO.
OH, he just came in so fast and like I
was saying on the backside of that rock
there is a diagonal route that has been
uh he's been coming out more and more
and more.
Yeah, I mean he was just he had to
break. There was nothing he could do but
you're you're breaking on a diagonal
route so back tire just came out a
little bit.
And down in that section that we've seen
take out so many people at such a
technical section. But as we said it is
a resurgent Gwin this year. I mean And
to be 2.2
up on this track in these conditions is
massive and he could even take from this
that the pace is there.
>> Yeah, definitely. I mean you could tell
the speed he was carrying. Super close
today for Aaron Gwin. I think I think
he's just going to take from it that he
is riding about as fast as he ever has.
2.2 up.
38 years old Aaron Gwin looking to be
back to his brilliant best but it's
Austin Dooley that wins the Red BULL
TENNESSEE NATIONAL. INCREDIBLE RIDE FOR
THAT YOUNG MAN.
OH, what a day we've had. It was a
superb race start to finish. The fastest
seeds knowing how hard they'd have to
push today. Both crashing out Gwin and
Shaw and there's Austin already with
Aaron. Great to see. Yeah.
That camaraderie and sportsmanship.
Seeing Neko Mulally back over there.
There's Mikey Della Salle. Same same
team for those two boys. Great day for
him. And there's Austin.
And this track I mean this was such an
amazing day, such an amazing day of
racing.
Pushed everyone to the absolute limit
but it was Austin Dooley that came out
on top. Look at that. The top four
riders on the same second. That's why
you're seeing riders push as hard as
that and crash out.
>> I mean look at that. I mean .004 between
first and second and then .9 between
first and third. And there are those
Gibson Les Paul guitars. Only one person
in this commentary booth can play one. I
can tell you that.
>> [laughter]
>> Really good podium. Good to see I mean
just a almost a year from the day come
back from the broken pelvis to take
that win. Amazing result for Austin
Dooley.
I feel insane with the win. I didn't
expect it. There's a lot of heavy
hitters and I know I'm riding well but
like I don't know exactly how well I'm
riding.
Not the greatest results last last year
and but I had a good winter training
here and riding here all the time with
this being my home mountain. Um I felt
good on track and was ready to lay one
down today which is what I did. I've
never even touched a guitar. I don't
know how to play a thing but I got a
sick guitar now so maybe I should try. I
don't know. Might might have to.
Uh it's for sure a big boost of
confidence. Um after last year and
I feel like I was kind of lacking some
confidence like
hard to believe in myself sometimes so
to come away with a result like this
definitely ups the confidence and
it's early on in the season so excited
to keep trying to build and keep
building up the speed up for the the
races later in the year.
Well, an absolutely massive day for
Austin Dooley there. I mean an
absolutely massive performance. What's
he just done? Well, I mean to come here
after last year where he had a broken
pelvis getting carted off almost a year
to the day come back and win this race.
And this this race is is no joke. You're
in rarefied air winning this race.
The margins today were incredible. .004
in front of second place Kolb Swedo and
then
.1 less than .1 ahead of Mikey Della
Salle is that Absolutely unbelievable
and and no doubt you know I spoke to him
afterwards he said the run it was so
fast it was scary fast and we saw that
with Aaron Gwin. I mean he was 2 seconds
up when he went down as well as Luca
Shaw you know the number one and two
seeds both crashing out. Difficult to
win this race. Uh it's just
you you really had to be on the edge.
There was nobody that had a really fast
run that that said oh that was smooth.
It's a gnarly track. It was super super
skiddy super pebbly no traction to be
had.
>> you had to push hard which is exactly
what Eleonora Ostegaard did in the
women's. Back to back wins for her.
The unbelievable thing is that she's
still a junior this year right? What?
Are you for real?
>> [laughter]
>> I mean
Eleonora like well thank goodness me I
got another year. I mean the poise to be
able to put that run down yesterday
yeah to go even faster today. And then
her sister as well.
Right up there the Logar sisters and
then Kaylee Skelton current national
champ. We've got some heavy hitters.
It's been an incredible weekend. I've
loved it. It's brilliant to see the
sport of downhill doing so well so
healthy here in the USA. Massive
entries. Helio I want to thank you. It's
been brilliant fun and I want to thank
everyone at home for watching as well
and we'll see you next year from the Red
Bull Tennessee National.